AURÉLIE JOSSERAND

Experience Designer

www.ajosserand.com @ josserand.n.aurelie@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/aurelie-josserand @ 405 503 7341

PROFILE

Over the past ten years, I've built products for companies, businesses and government entities around the globe with a focus on design, usability, accessibility and inclusivity.

While the products I design have been in the built environment, the skills I have learned as an architect and designer are all applicable to digital design. From working with multi-disciplinary teams, to iterating through design concepts and working with stakeholders, I am committed to meeting client expectations while creating great user experiences.

EDUCATION

CODECADEMY

Front-End Engineer track Winter 2022 to present

BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE

University of Oklahoma Oklahoma, 2011-2012

BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE

Ecole Nationale Superieure d'Architecture France, 2007-2010

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent French - Native

OTHER QUALIFICATIONS

Registered Architect **EDAC** Accredited LEED Accredited BD+C

EXPERIENCE

Smithgroup, Washington, District of Columbia

2015 to present - Designer & Architect

- Develops innovative and visually compelling concepts for experiential spaces, while considering human-centered design best practices.
- Leads the 3D production process by mentoring peers and implementing the latest trends and innovations in AR, VR and real-time rendering.
- Manages system coordination on large scale projects involving multi-disciplinary teams of engineers and designers.
- Involved in all project phases from early design iterations to project documentation.
- Promotes the company brand through online and in person community activities and organization involvement.

Miles Associates, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

2012 to 2015 - Project Coordinator

- Led 3D visualizations effort by creating compelling digital experiences and identifying software and workflow needs.
- Developed the company Website Design using Squarespace CMS.
- Assisted project teams on crafting design, construction documentation and project pursuits.

AWARDS & LEADERSHIP

Guest Speaker & Workshop Moderator

Howard University, 2024

Lead Panel Moderator

Summer Leadership Summit 2019

Guest Speaker

George Washington University, 2020

Next General Scholar

Summer Leadership Summit 2018

TOOLBOX

Figma & XD

Real Time 3D	3DSMAX	HTML5	Project Management
AR/VR	AutoCAD	CSS	Human Centered Design
Adobe Photoshop	Lumion	JavaScript	Web Development
Adobe Illustrator	Sketchup	ReactJS	Responsive Design
Adobe After Effect	Revit	Mocha	
Adobe Premier Pro	Lidar	Nodes.js	

GIT

Dynamo